# **Luciano Schmarsow**

IT Technician
Full Stack Web Developer

(+351) 963 309 798 – Lisboa, Portugal

ldschmarsow@gmail.com

linkedin.com/in/lucianoschmarsow

github.com/clarkos (

lucianosch.com



in

Support Technician with over 15 years of experience in troubleshooting and maintenance of computer equipment, with skills in platform administration and security systems. Interpersonal skills developed through collaboration with multidisciplinary teams, allowing clear and effective communication with users. Skilled in web design with experience in HTML, CSS and CMS content managers, trained in Full Stack Web Development acquiring skills in JavaScript, React, Express, Java and Databases. Strong motivation to learn and grow in a challenging work environment. Advanced level of English, with C1 certification.

#### PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE:

#### Support Technician (2008-2022)

Started a personal venture, which provide support and maintenance services to individuals and companies. Some tasks that was performed focused on preventive maintenance and updating personal use devices. I also provided services to companies, of which I can mention some professional challenges:

## La Casa del Telgo, Mar del Plata (2020-2022)

- Responsible for the maintenance, repair, and installation of computer equipment and operating systems.
- Replacement of components and implementation of computer numerical control (CNC) machines.
- Administration and configuration of distributed work systems on Linux and Windows platforms.

#### • Independent Security Systems installer, Mar del Plata (2015 - 2020)

- Installation and maintenance of video surveillance equipment with remote access.
- Assistance and support in incidents related to the operation and performance of security systems.
- Definition and configuration of system user permissions, including remote access credentials.

#### Bespa Autoelevadores, Mar del Plata (2011)

- Identification and resolution of faults in the wiring of an existing network system, which prevented access to the central server.
- Manual inspection of the network layout and location of the problem in a section which material wear was deteriorated due to exposure to climatic effects.
- Replacement of the wiring and relocation to protect the material and guarantee its integrity.
- Increase in system speed and productivity through the implementation of new materials and re-routing of the wiring, allowing for the incorporation of new terminals and devices.
- Benefits for the company by improving system performance and increasing its capacity.
- Development and implementation of security and contingency policies, reducing the risk of information loss and increasing data confidentiality.

## Security Systems installer on INSURED Security, Mar del Plata (2005-2008)

- Installation, maintenance and repair of perimeter security equipment.
- Technical support to users, ensuring efficient system operation.
- Development and implementation of security policies, reducing the risk of criminal incidents.

## **PROJECTS**

## Full Stack Web Developer - Groove Music

feb. 2023 - mar. 2023

Academic Experience.

Henry Bootcamp, Buenos Aires, Argentina.

A team project to create a platform for selling tickets to music events in Mar del Plata. It was implemented authentication, search, combined filtering, sorting, email sending, payment gateway. I was responsible for deploying services to production, reviewing code changes, monitoring project structure, refining functions, and resolving code conflicts. Followed modular approach and SCRUM methodologies for successful implementation.

Frontend: React 18, React-Admin, Redux, React Router, Material UI, Firebase

Backend: ExpressJS, Cloudinary, MailGen, MercadoPago, Firebase

Database: PostgreSQL y Sequelize.

Repository: <a href="http://github.com/clarkos/new-proj-grupal">http://github.com/clarkos/new-proj-grupal</a>

Demo: <a href="https://groove-tickets.vercel.app/">https://groove-tickets.vercel.app/</a>

## Full Stack Web Developer – FoodFinder

dec. 2022 - jan. 2023

Academic Experience.

Henry Bootcamp, Buenos Aires, Argentina.

The project involved the implementation of a wide range of technical skills, allowing for search, combined filtering, and the addition of new recipes, among others. This platform provides nutritional information while allowing users to obtain a list based on the ingredients they request.

Frontend: React 18, Redux, React Router, Javascript, HTML5, CSS3

Backend: ExpressJS

**Database**: PostgreSQL y Sequelize.

**Repository**: <a href="https://github.com/clarkos/PI-Food">https://foodpi-aqz4.onrender.com</a>

#### Frontend Web Developer - Life Door Ministries

Jun. 2015 - Mar. 2017

Volunteer Web Development Mar del Plata, Argentina

The site was implemented to increase the reach of content generated from social media, allow for the playback of live-streamed events, and provide a listing of OnDemand videos obtained from YouTube. The implementation of SEO optimization placed the site

within the top 5 results in Google searches, increased live event participation by 33%, and increased YouTube channel subscriptions by 48%.

At this moment, I'm working on an updated version of the site, with new technologies and layout improvements, using the following technologies.

Frontend: React 18, NextJS 13, Tailwind, Typescript

**Backend**: Solidity.io **Database**: MongoDB

Site: <a href="https://www.puertadevida.com">https://www.puertadevida.com</a>

#### **TECHNOLOGIES:**

- Knowledge of Windows and Linux operating systems.
- Experience in implementing IoT solutions based on Arduino platform.
- Experience in implementing networks and security systems.
- Knowledge of monitoring tools, performance analysis, and recovery environments.
- Experience in developing web and desktop applications.
- Knowledge of programming languages such as Javascript, Java and Python.
- Knowledge of programming frameworks such as React, ExpressJS and NextJS

## PROFESSIONAL TRAINING

- Full Stack Web Developer. Henry Bootcamp. 700 hours of theoretical-practical training. 2023.
- Full Stack Web Developer. Oracle Next Education Program AluraLatam. 350 hours of theoretical-practical training. 2023.
- Computer Technician. Technical School №5, Mar del Plata. 2001.

## **COMPLEMENTARY TRAINING**

- HTML & CSS: Froms Buildings. LinkedIn Learning. 2022.
- BigData: Fundamentals: Technics and concepts. LinkedIn Learning. 2022.
- BigData: Data analisys. LinkedIn Learning. 2022.
- BigData: Data visulization. LinkedIn Learning. 2022.
- Linux Unhatched. NDG Cisco Net Acad. 2022.

## **LANGUAJES:**

Spanish: NativoEnglish: C1Portuguese: B1